Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Postcards, 731 (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
  - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C., Circa 1932; 1 Photographic Prints
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the exterior of Dr. Glanx sanatorium at the Physical and Dietetic Institute in Helwan (Sanatorium Dr. Glanx (Institut Physico Dietique - no. 182), Circa 1932; ref595; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Helwan, Egypt; Egypt; Hospitals; Buildings; Architecture; English Writing; Sanitariums/Sanatoriums
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps from the breakwater (Port Said: From the Breakwater no. 501), Circa 1932; ref596; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Statues/Sculptures; Monuments/Memorials; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Individual Portraits; English Writing
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps at Port Said (no. 500), 2 November 1932; ref597; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; English Writing; Port Said, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Individual Portraits; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Monuments/Memorials
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the exterior of The Mosque at Helouan (no. 184), Circa 1932; ref598; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Helwan, Egypt; Architecture; Buildings; Mosques; Religious Sites; English Writing
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the exterior of Sanatorium Fouad I. in Helwan (no. 181), Circa 1932; ref599; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Architecture; Buildings; Helwan, Egypt; English Writing; Sanitariums/Sanatoriums
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of men with two camels on sand dunes (no. 291), Circa 1932; ref600; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Deserts; Animals; Camels; Men; Regional/National Dress; English Writing; Landscapes; Egypt
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of a woman standing besides a man riding a camel (Rest in the Desert) (no. 296), Circa 1932; ref601; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Deserts; Men; English Writing; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Camels; Women; Egypt
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the Office of the Suez Canal Company at Port Said, Circa 1932; ref602; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; English Writing; Boats/Ships; Transportation
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the Canal Company's Offices at Port Said (The Canal Company's Pretty Offices) (no. 306), Circa 1932; ref603; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; English Writing; French Writing; Offices
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of the entrance to the Mena House Hotel (no. 276), Circa 1932; ref604; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Palm Trees; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Women; English Writing
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of men with camels in a desert (no. 189), Circa 1932; ref605; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Deserts; Animals; Camels; English Writing; Men; Egypt
    - J. J. Smith. R. A. S. C. Series - A postcard of nightfall at the Pyramids in Cairo (no. 170), Circa 1932; ref606; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
      Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture; Pyramids; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers
  - A postcard of a man on a camel with the Pyramids in the background., Circa 1904-1939; ref607; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Animals; Camels; Men; Regional/National Dress; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Architecture
  - A postcard of a man on a camel in front of the The Pyramids in Cairo (no.165), Circa 1904-1939; ref608; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Regional/National Dress; Nile River; Rivers; Buildings; English Writing
  - A hand-colored postcardof a watercolour by R. Barratt of a man in Ibn Tuloon Mosque in Cairo, Circa 1908-1930; ref609; Medici Society Ld, London (England) (1908-present); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Mosque of Ibn Tulun; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Cairo, Egypt; Men
  - A postcard of the general view of Port Said (no.2), Circa 1885-1920; ref610; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; Lighthouses; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Boats/Ships; Transportation; English Writing; French Writing; Port Said, Egypt
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Gameh-el-Sheikh Mosque in Alexandria (Mosquée Gameh-el-Sheikh), Circa 1873-1922; ref611; Emil Pinkau & Cie, Soc. An., Leipzig (Germany) (Active 1904-1945); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; French Writing; Buildings; Architecture
  - A postcard of a mural painting on the Tomb of Ti in Sakkara (Sakkara Tomb of Ti - Mural Painting) (no. 1136), Circa 1904-1939; ref612; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Tombs/Mausoleums; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Saqqara, Egypt; English Writing; Religious Sites
  - A postcard of a man on a camel by the Suez Canal, Circa 1904-1939; ref613; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; English Writing; Nile River; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Animals; Camels; Men; Egypt; French Writing; German Writing
  - A postcard of the Arabian bazaar near Fort-Napoleon in Alexandria, Circa 1890-1940; ref614; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Individual Portraits; Men; Children; Animals; English Writing; Shops; Architecture; Streets/Roads
  - A hand-colored postcard of a painting of Luxor with the mountains of Thebes (no. 136), Circa 1890-1940; ref615; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Paintings; Luxor, Egypt; Thebes, Egypt; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Individual Portraits; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of a Muezzin giving the call to prayer (no. 40), Circa 1902-1912; ref616; Lichtenstern & Harari, Commission Agents, Cairo (Egypt) (Active circa 1901-1908); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; English Writing; Architecture; Mosques; Buildings; Men; Regional/National Dress; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Arabic Writing; Praying; Religious Sites; Egypt
  - A postcard of ships near an open Kasr-el-Nil Bridge in Cairo., Circa 1890-1940; ref617; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Bridges; Architecture; Men; French Writing; Nile River; Rivers
  - A postcard of The Pyramids of Giza (no. 54), 1 March 1938; ref618; Zogos & Co. - Cairo, Egypt; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Architecture; Nile River; Rivers; Giza, Egypt; English Writing; Palm Trees; Animals; Camels; Individual Portraits; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A hand-colored postcard of the road to the Pyramids in Cairo, Circa 1899-1908; ref619; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Landscapes; English Writing; Rivers; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Pyramids
  - A hand-colored postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps (Statue de Ferdinand de Lesseps) (no. 337), Circa 1890-1940; ref620; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Seas; Port Said, Egypt; Mediterranean Sea; Monuments/Memorials; Statues/Sculptures; French Writing; Buildings; Water
  - A postcard of "Banks of the Nile" a painting by Ella Du Cane (Series no. 10), Circa 1913-1935; ref621; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Paintings; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers; Water; English Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of the interior of the Mosque of Mohamed Ali at the Citadel in Cairo, Circa 1890-1940; ref622; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; English Writing
  - A postcard of two lion statues on the Kasr-el-Nil Bridge in Cairo, Circa 1890-1940; ref623; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Horses; Bridges; Street Lamps; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Regional/National Dress; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Horses; Prams/Buggies/Strollers; Women; Hats; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads
  - A hand-colored postcard of an illustration of the Pyramids of Gizeh (Les pyramides de Gizeh)., Circa 1890-1940; ref624; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Architecture; Buildings; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Camels; Animals; Men; Regional/National Dress; Giza, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; German Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Works of the Suez Canal Company at Port Said (Ateliers de la cie du Canal de Suez, Circa 1890-1940; ref625; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A postcard of two people near the Pyramids during flood time, Circa 1904-1939; ref626; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; Buildings; Palm Trees; Men; Regional/National Dress; Nile River; Rivers; Water; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of the Pyramids and the Village during Nile Flood, Circa 1904-1939; ref627; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing
  - A postcard of a man on a camel in front of the Pyramid of Khafre (no. 171), Circa 1904-1939; ref628; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Palm Trees; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; English Writing; Camels; Animals; Men; Regional/National Dress; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of a man on a camel near The Great Sphinx and the Pyramids in Giza, Circa 1904-1939; ref629; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; English Writing; Animals; Camels; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A hand-colored postcard of merchants in Cairo (Le Caire Marchands des arbres)., Circa 1899-1908; ref630; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Animals; Camels; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
  - A postcard of the limestone statue of King Zoser (no. 700), Circa 1904-1939; ref631; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Egypt
  - A hand-colored postcard of the offices of the Suez Canal Company at Port Said (Bureaux de la cie du Canal de Suez), Circa 1890-1940; ref632; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; English Writing; Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Seas; Water; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of people sitting on the banks of the Suez Canal (Navire dans le Canal), Circa 1890-1940; ref633; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Seas; Water; Boats/Ships; Port Said, Egypt; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Men; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Mahmoudieh Canal in Alexandria, Circa 1890-1940; ref634; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Alexandria, Egypt; Canals; Water; Animals; Men; English Writing; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of a general view of Alexandria., Circa 1890-1940; ref635; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Seas; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; English Writing; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of an illustration of Cherif Pacha street in Alexandria, Circa 1890-1940; ref636; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Individual Portraits; Shops; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Men; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Architecture; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of the procession of the Mahmal (Holy Carpet) in Alexandria., Circa 1890-1926; ref637; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Alexandria, Egypt; Crowds; Parades/Processions; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Ceremony; English Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Streets/Roads
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps at Port Said (no. 777), Circa 1899-1908; ref638; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Monuments/Memorials; Statues/Sculptures; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; French Writing; Boats/Ships; Transportation; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of a painting of a domed building next to a stream in a village, Circa 1899-1908; ref639; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; Egypt; Palm Trees; Rivers; Water; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; Paintings; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A postcard of a road next to the Suez Canal, Circa 1930-1950; ref640; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Seas; Boats/Ships; English Writing; Transportation; Suez, Egypt; Landscapes
  - A postcard of a birds-eye view of Port Said, Circa 1890-1940; ref641; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; English Writing; Buildings; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Delta Barrage, Circa 1899-1908; ref642; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Bridges; Architecture; Dams/Barrages; Cairo, Egypt; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Water
  - A postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps at Port Said, Circa 1899-1940; ref643; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Monuments/Memorials; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing
  - A postcard of boats in the west bay in Alexandria (no.5)., Circa 1890-1940; ref644; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Men; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Seas; Water; Buildings; English Writing; French Writing
  - A postcard of the port with boats and the Suez Canal offices at Port Said (Le Port)., July 1915; ref645; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; French Writing; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture
  - A postcard of a general view of the City of the Dead in Cairo., unknown; ref646; Unknown; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt
- Markets of the World, 1905; ref730; Keystone-Underwood, Keystone View Co. 219 East 44th Street, New York (USA). (E-records Digital copy only - 030_ref506-ref516)
  Egypt; Markets; Animals; Agriculture/Farms; Workers